<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>assignments on PHI 010</title>
    <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi10/tags/assignments/</link>
    <description>Recent content in assignments on PHI 010</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 09:58:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://chreliot.github.io/phi10/tags/assignments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 2</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi10/assignments/assignment-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 09:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi10/assignments/assignment-2/</guid>
      <description>Write at least 1300 words in response to one of the numbered topics below. Make sure to present arguments clearly. Also remember that a criticism of an argument cannot simply describe a different perspective or support a different conclusion; instead it must argue that there is a problem either with the target argument&#39;s logic or with one or more of its premises.
Write as if you&#39;re addressing someone who is not in the class and does not have a background in philosophy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 1</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi10/assignments/assignment-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 09:23:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi10/assignments/assignment-1/</guid>
      <description>Pick a statement that reflects something you believe. This assignment might be slightly easier if it is a statement that not everyone believes, but it will work fine either way. It should be something that you want to think more about, and maybe a statement for which the justification is not obvious. The statement will function as the conclusion of three arguments you will create, following the instructions below. So, after you&#39;ve picked a statement, do each of the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting Grades</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi10/info/interpreting-grades/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi10/info/interpreting-grades/</guid>
      <description>This note about grading and interpreting grades just adds some detail to what the course syllabus already says about grading.
4-point scale Grades in this course are assigned and calculated using Hofstra&#39;s 4-point scale (described here in the Hofstra Bulletin). Following the Bulletin, the alphabetical grades, including plus (+) and minus (–), have the following 4-point scale values (and vice versa):
   letter 4pt Student’s academic performance …     A 4.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>