<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>topics on PHI 010</title>
    <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi10/tags/topics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in topics on PHI 010</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 08:34:23 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://chreliot.github.io/phi10/tags/topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 5: Knowing and Being</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi10/topics/knowing-and-being/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 08:34:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi10/topics/knowing-and-being/</guid>
      <description>Here we meet skepticism, the worry that we can&amp;rsquo;t have genuine knowledge, and then accounts of how we can have knowledge. This introduces us to Epistemology. We then see how epistemology connects with Metaphysics, in seeing how accounts of how we know are related to accounts of what we are. We&amp;rsquo;ll do this by focusing on two early modern philosophers and their critics.
Reading  René Descartes, “First Meditation and Second Meditation” from Meditations on First Philosophy in Which Are Demonstrated the Existence of God and the Distinction Between the Human Soul and Body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 4: Law</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi10/topics/law/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 22:50:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi10/topics/law/</guid>
      <description>Next we turn to when, whether, and why are compelled to obey laws.
Reading  Plato, Crito (early 4th century BCE), translated by Cathal Woods and Ryan Pack (2012), available from SSRN, or this alternative version. Read pages 1, 2, and 7–9 of this 10-page text (the rest is optional). Martin Luther King Jr., “Letter from Birmingham Jail,”1 (1963), available here. Consider reading the whole thing, but our discussion will concern paragraphs 9–18 (from “You may well ask: ‘Why direct action?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 3: Logic</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi10/topics/logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 22:30:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi10/topics/logic/</guid>
      <description>A basic organizing structure for philosophy is the argument. Arguments are sets of statements where one of the statements is a conclusion. What knits them together is logic. We will think about what arguments are and then learn some basic ideas of logic.
Reading  “Basic Ideas and Tools,” Chapter 1 of A Modern Formal Logic Primer by Edmund Teller, sections 1-1 to 1-4, or equivalently pages 1–10 of Volume 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 2: Determinism and Freedom</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi10/topics/determinism-and-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 22:25:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi10/topics/determinism-and-freedom/</guid>
      <description>This brief topic offers a basic philosophical problem with a very long history. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting problem, but we&amp;rsquo;re also starting with it to get a first look at philosophical methodology and the structure of arguments and counter-arguments.
Reading  Daniel Dennett, Elbow Room: The Varieties of Free Will Worth Wanting (1984), 2 brief excerpts, 4 pages (Blackboard)  See also  In the Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy:  Causal Determinism Free Will Compatibilism Skepticism about Moral Responsibility  Entertaining movies on this topic include Memento and Minority Report.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 1: What Is Philosophy?</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi10/topics/what-is-philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 21:33:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi10/topics/what-is-philosophy/</guid>
      <description>Prominent philosopher Martha Nussbaum was recently asked “How would you define the role of a philosopher in today’s world?” She answered:
 I wouldn’t. There are so many good ways to engage with the world, and each philosopher should figure it out for herself. I don’t like telling others what to do.
 Still, philosophy has a history. And its history involves people doing specific things and calling them “philosophy,” and not calling other things “philosophy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>